<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>geospatial on Parsecs Reach</title>
    <link>https://parsecsreach.org/tags/geospatial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in geospatial on Parsecs Reach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2022</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 07:38:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://parsecsreach.org/tags/geospatial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Normalized Difference Vegetation Index</title>
      <link>https://parsecsreach.org/post/ndvi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 07:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parsecsreach.org/post/ndvi/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s topic: NDVI. This is another post that started life as a thread over on mastodon.
What the heck is that? It&amp;rsquo;s an acronym (sorry) it stands for normalized difference vegetation index. Short version it&amp;rsquo;s a proxy for how much healthy plant life there is.
It will be a number between -1 and 1. -1 being a clean concrete slab or similar. 1 being an impossibly healthy rainforest canopy.
The way this one works is comparing the difference between absorption of near infrared light and red light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>180 Degrees</title>
      <link>https://parsecsreach.org/post/180_degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 19:48:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parsecsreach.org/post/180_degrees/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post started out as a thread on mastodon. Please follow me there if you&amp;rsquo;d like to see this sort of thing early
Lets start talking about something I wish I didn&amp;rsquo;t know as much about as I do.
The 180 degree line! +/-180 degrees longitude.
It is not the same thing as the international date line, that&amp;rsquo;s defined politically which lots of wiggles through the pacific islands.
The 180 degree line only crosses two countries, Russia and Fiji.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding flatroofs with QGIS</title>
      <link>https://parsecsreach.org/post/flatroofs_with_qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://parsecsreach.org/post/flatroofs_with_qgis/</guid>
      <description>A little while ago I attended the Climathon kic event/hackathon in Bristol at my old university. The event was to come up with solutions that could help with pollution in the city. There were not a lot of people who turned up so we formed a single team. The idea we came up with was to create an incentive for people with flat roofs to put plants on them. This meant we needed to be able to find flat roofs in the city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
